

# **ULUGBEK ZAYNIEV**

• DETAILS •

bek.zayniev@gmail.com

LINKSLinkedIn

SKILLS

Creative Problem Solving
Product Management
Business Development
Business Operations
Marketing and Sales
Customer Service
Leadership and Management
Agile Project Management
Coaching and Mentoring

LANGUAGES

English
Russian
Uzbek
Italian

#### PROFILE

Customer- and result-oriented leader with 11+ years experience in managing all aspects of strategy, sales, product development, operations, marketing, general business, pricing, customer retention, product innovation, scrum teams, B2B development and compliance of SaaS and E-commerce Marketplaces. Certified Team Coach, bring people together and like to motivate and inspire others to run along.

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### CEO at Oyster Inc, USA

March 2020 — Present

U.S. based an Ed Tech service for children.

- Operated a start-up company that grew to employ and manage 25 staff members in the first year: product designers, product managers, marketing, b2b sales, Amazon sales, support, operations, analytics, finance
- Led the launch of a new line of ages 3+ STEM kits in just 5 months
- Organized all the business processes in remote in 1 month during COVID-19
- Discovered and save \$30K on inventory and freight costs
- Handled over 100 customer development interviews with subscribers and schools by zoom
- Sold over \$200K to schools with net profit >45%
- Implemented and ensured compliance with OKRs

# Project & Business Development Leader at Open Group

May 2019 — January 2020

Leading trade marketing agency. Managed international projects and new business & products development.

- Realized first international project within one month in Ukraine with GP 50%, client Huawei: mystery shop audit, >200 stores, 2 contractors
- Launched & realized international projects in 4 countries, Israel, Jordan, Georgia & Azerbaijan, NP is 40%, client Beko: in-store audit and product training, >1000 stores, 10 contractors
- Opened a local subsidiary in Kazakhstan from scratch
- · Generated product positioning for new SFA and Image Recognition software
- Created new company positioning & presentation based on 8P

# Senior Product and Business Development Manager at Sharp Electronics

June 2016 — May 2019

Managed all CE categories (7 cat), marketing and sales strategy.

- Increased general company sales turnover by 18% and gross profit by 25%
- Launched new products from scratch in REF (sales up 16%), AP (sales up 22%), MWO (sales increased by 5 times)
- Launched new categories from "0" TV & Audio
- Decreased purchase prices by 10% from global suppliers and increased payment terms 2 times
- Activated new retail partners in regions 5 second tier partners
- Led the sales team 5 managers

- Conducted an audit at factories in China, Egypt, Russia and Turkey
- Implemented CPFR stock out rate and aging stock decreased

# **Product Manager at Ricoh**

August 2015 — April 2016

Managed 150 SKU in office printer and MFP categories.

- Increased core business sell-in and sell-out by 100%
- Conducted and organized 15 trainings for 50 partners with more than 400 participants
- Implemented telemarketing project with one specialist under my coordination
- Successfully launched 2 new products (positioning, pricing, sales forecast, promotion plan)
- Created new marketing tools (brochures, videos, marketing campaigns, motivation programs)
- Introduced new business strategy of product sales (models' diversification repositioning and new price establishment)

# Product Manager at Samsung Electronics

August 2012 — August 2015

Managed over 200 SKUs in home appliance department, including all marketing activities.

- Market share 11 in premium segment (Refrigerator, 2015)
- Improved profit +9p. (Refrigerator 2014-2015)
- Launched new MWO (20+3L), WM and REF models
- Created and implemented the tools of profit simulation and sales plan simulation for the whole HA department appreciated by top management
- The best PSI management and benchmark analysis of products in the department
- Coordinated and implemented internet price monitoring software improved the control of the on-line stores' prices

# EDUCATION

Master, Higher School of Economics

2007 - 2012

Graduated with High Honors in International Business, Math, Logic

# COURSES

Team Coaching in Business, CCE ICF MentorExpert

2022

Coaching Skills, International University Global Coaching

2021

Data-driven Product Management Simulator, GoPractice Inc

2020

**Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner, IBM** 

2019